GBENGA ADEYEMI

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER [♥] ILORIN, 240241, NIGERIA [♥] +234-808-677-1870

• DETAILS •

No 6 Sanni Close GRA Ilorin, 240241 Nigeria +234-808-677-1870 addegbenga@gmail.com

ONLINE MEDIA

Portfoli o

<u>Linkedl n</u>

Github

• SKILLS •

HTML5

MongoDB

Node.js

Git

HTML & CSS

React

JavaScript

Sass

Figma

Express.js

Socket.io

Gsap

• LANGUAGES •

English

HOBBIES

Chess, Games, Codewar Lover, Blog, Hackathon, Dance

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated self-taught web developer with three years of experience in Front-end and Back-end development. Experienced with React, JavaScript, Node JS, Express, CSS, HTML, MongoDB, GSAP. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

EDUCATION

B.Tech (Geology and Science), Federal University of Technology, Minna, Minna

September 2015 — September 2021

Graduated with a Second Class (Lower) Honors.

RECENT PROJECTS

- Maze Game (React) (<u>GitHub Repo</u>)
- Image Compressor (Node js, Express, Sharp) (<u>GitHub Repo</u>)
- Weather Application (weather-forecast007.netlify.app)
- Authentication System (https://myprofile007.netlify.app/)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Quality Assurance Personnel at Montech Software Studio, USA (Remote)

November 2021 — Till Date

- Drive innovation and streamline overall testing processes.
- Develop standards and procedures to determine product quality and release readiness
- Perform manual and automated testing
- Research new tools, technologies, and testing processes.
- Review user interfaces for consistency and functionality

Full Stack Developer at Lenx, United Kingdom (Remote)

November 2020 — September 2021

- Implement User Authentication system with JSON Web Token to specific design specifications and requirements for an e-commerce marketplace in development.
- Connected API with Redux to the Front-End.
- Implement Client-Side Search System with Redux-Search library
- Responsible for the hiring, on-boarding, training, and mentoring of two new talents.
- Work in tandem with other team members to implement features and functionality
- Provide advice about functionality on projects using chosen MEAN stack technologies (HTML, CSS, JS, React, Redux, MongoDB)

ä

Full-Stack Developer (Freelance) at Audal Labs (http://audallabs.com), Australia (Remote)

October 2021

Converted Figma design files to pixel perfect code using sass and HTML.
Design and implemented the animated carousel header for a client website with GSAP and React.

Co-Founder (Full-Stack Developer) at Qwikker, Nigeria

January 2021

- A digital business card that allows user to have all their social media links in one place. It makes it easier for user to share with clients and reach more audience.
- Beta version scheduled for release, October 2021.

Back-End Developer at Saucecode Hackathon (Remote), Nigeria

2020

- Developed fully functional API for the Edtech startup idea we came up with including user authentication as well as user CRUD functionalities.
- In collaboration with me team member, we made it to the top 10 team of the competition which was a great achievement.

INTERNSHIPS

Frontend Developer at HNG, Nigeria, remote

2021

Front-End Developer at Zuri Training (Remote), Nigeria

June 2020

Trainee Field Geologist at Lower Niger River Basin Dev. Authority, Ilorin

January 2019 — July 2019

*

VOLUNTEER

Back-End Implementation for the faculty of Physical Science e-Voting System, Minna, Nigeria

June 2020 — July 2020